# ISAAC WAWERU KARIITHI

Email Address: isaactrisonwaweru@gmail.com

**Contact number**: +254705992717/254114884275

Physical Address: 284-80403 Kwale

City: Nairobi

Country: Kenya

Citizenship: Kenyan

Website: https://portfolio-web-app-theta.vercel.app/

Github: <a href="https://github.com/Trisonweru/">https://github.com/Trisonweru/</a>

### **BACKGROUND**

I'm a software developer with 3 years of experience in full-stack web development of a variety of domains and\_tech stacks. My strongest skills are ReactJS/NextJS, AngularJS, Redux, Node.js, Typescript, TailwindCSS, Material UI Kit, GraphQl, Apollo Client/Server, Prisma, Docker, MongoDB, MySQL, and PostgreSQL. I'm experienced in designing good UI with Figma and efficient web backends for rapid scaling. I have significant experience working with IT infrastructures to maintain or configure services due to my role as ICT Officer at ME Moringa For Life. I am flexible with different technologies and methodologies.

# PROFICIENT TECH-STACKS

- 1) ReactJS/NextJS + Typescript + TailwindCSS + Prisma + Postgresql/Mysql/MongoDB
- 2) ReactJS/NextJS + Typescript + TailwindCSS + Graphql + MongoDB/Mysql

### FAMILIAR TECH-STACKS

- 1) Angular + Typescript + TailwindCSS + Prisma + Postgresql/Mysql/MongoDB
- 2) Angular+ Typescript + TailwindCSS + Graphql + MongoDB/Mysql

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

# TheList - <a href="https://the-list-gray.vercel.app/">https://the-list-gray.vercel.app/</a>

An app to help users browse or search different categories of movies save them to favorite lists, watch lists, or custom-created lists. The user can share all the custom-created lists with users within the app.

Github - https://github.com/Trisonweru/TheList

Technologies – NextJS/ReactJS, REST API, Google Authentication, Tailwind CSS, Material UI Toolkit, Prisma, and PostgreSQL

## NextAmazona - https://next-amazona.vercel.app/

An e-commerce web application that helps users shop online. Users can search or browse items and add them to the cart.

Technologies - NextJS/ReactJS, Prisma and PostgreSQL

### MoneyPlug - https://next-ts-prisma-tailwindcss.vercel.app/

A prototype project that helps users transfer money to each other within the app. The sender can convert money to one of the available currencies and the receiver can receive money to the respective account.

Github - https://github.com/Trisonweru/next-ts-prisma-tailwindcss

Technologies - NextJS/ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, Material UI Toolkit, Prisma, and PostgreSQL

### meetme.com - https://meetme-com-next-js-tailwind-css-prisma-postgresql.vercel.app

meetme.com is an ongoing project on phase 1 where I was supposed to develop an events scheduler where users can share a link for clients to book their events. The required sections completed are UI design and Implementation, creating a default event, viewing bookings, cancel bookings, booking link and google calendar events API integration.

Github - https://github.com/Trisonweru/meetme.com-NextJS-TailwindCSS-Prisma-Postgresql

Technologies – NextJS/ReactJS, Google Calendar API, Tailwind CSS, Material UI Toolkit, Prisma, and PostgreSQL

#### Discounter - https://github.com/Trisonweru/discountApp-Shopify-GraphQL-API-React-Next

A tool to help Shopify merchants create and manage discounts from their Shopify e-commerce store.

Technologies - NextJS, GraphQL, Apollo Client, Shopify GraphQL API, CSS

### **EDUCATION**

Kibabii University – Bsc Computer Science – September 2015 – November 2019

Second Class Lower Degree – 58.25 Points

Nduluku High School – Kenya Certificate of Secondary School(KCSE) – February 2010 – November 2014

Mean Grade - B 65 Points

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Freelance Web Developer – February 2021- Present

React with hooks, Angular, Figma design tool, Typescript, Styled Components, Material UI, Bootstrap, SCSS, NextJs & Redux | NodeJs with Express | GraphQL, Prisma | MongoDB, Postgresql, Firebase & MySQL | Python with Flask & Django | Git with Github

ICT Officer - MEmoringa For Life - March 2020 - Nov 2021 - https://memoringaforlife.com

WordPress Design and Development | e-commerce - store management and Online Order Processing | Networking Administration & Network Maintenance | IT Infrastructure Maintainance | Social Media Management | Product Designing with Adobe Illustrator

Software Developer – Internship - Technology Partners Limited – July 2019 - Feb 2020

React js with Styled Components & Material UI | NodeJs with Express | MySQL | Photoshop

# **COMPUTING SKILLS**

Javascript | React/Next | Typescript

Prisma | Angular | NodeJs

HTML | CSS | SCCS | Boostrap

| Material UI Kit | GraphQL

### **AWARDS**

Best Performing KCSE Student in

Nduluku High School - 2019

LANGUAGES

English | Swahili | Gikuyu

### **INTERESTS**

Web Design|Travel|

Technology | AI | Exercise |

Problem solving

# **REFEREES**

James Mwambingu - HR – Memoringa For Life EPZ LTD - 0713211907

Andrew Sikuku - Software Developer - Professional Mentor - 0777405414

John Gekombe - Lecturer - Kibabii University - 0721970694